// import shuffleArray from "../helpers/shuffleArray.js";
// import { getRandomItem } from "../helpers/shuffleAnswer.js";

export const StarWarsQuestions = [
  {
    question: "Who is Luke Skywalker's father?",
    options: ["Darth Vader", "Obi-Wan Kenobi", "Yoda", "Emperor Palpatine"],
    correctAnswer: "Darth Vader",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Han Solo's ship?",
    options: ["Millennium Falcon", "Star Destroyer", "X-wing", "TIE Fighter"],
    correctAnswer: "Millennium Falcon",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the Jedi Master who trains Luke Skywalker?",
    options: ["Yoda", "Obi-Wan Kenobi", "Mace Windu", "Qui-Gon Jinn"],
    correctAnswer: "Yoda",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Darth Vader's Super Star Destroyer?",
    options: ["Executor", "Death Star", "Finalizer", "Devastator"],
    correctAnswer: "Executor",
  },
  {
    question: "Who shot first in the Mos Eisley Cantina?",
    options: ["Han Solo", "Greedo", "Chewbacca", "Luke Skywalker"],
    correctAnswer: "Han Solo",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Boba Fett's ship?",
    options: ["Slave I", "Millennium Falcon", "Tantive IV", "Razor Crest"],
    correctAnswer: "Slave I",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is Rey's grandfather?",
    options: ["Emperor Palpatine", "Luke Skywalker", "Obi-Wan Kenobi", "Snoke"],
    correctAnswer: "Emperor Palpatine",
  },
  {
    question: "What planet is home to Chewbacca and the Wookiees?",
    options: ["Kashyyyk", "Endor", "Tatooine", "Hoth"],
    correctAnswer: "Kashyyyk",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the color of Mace Windu's lightsaber?",
    options: ["Purple", "Blue", "Green", "Red"],
    correctAnswer: "Purple",
  },
  {
    question: "Who plays the role of Han Solo in 'Solo: A Star Wars Story'?",
    options: [
      "Alden Ehrenreich",
      "Harrison Ford",
      "Chris Pratt",
      "Anthony Ingruber",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Alden Ehrenreich",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the planet that the first Death Star destroys?",
    options: ["Alderaan", "Naboo", "Coruscant", "Jakku"],
    correctAnswer: "Alderaan",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the bounty hunter that captures Han Solo in 'The Empire Strikes Back'?",
    options: ["Boba Fett", "Jango Fett", "Dengar", "Bossk"],
    correctAnswer: "Boba Fett",
  },
  {
    question: "What species is Yoda?",
    options: ["Unknown", "Wookiee", "Ewok", "Gungan"],
    correctAnswer: "Unknown",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the actor that plays Obi-Wan Kenobi in the original trilogy?",
    options: [
      "Alec Guinness",
      "Ewan McGregor",
      "James Arnold Taylor",
      "Liam Neeson",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Alec Guinness",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the desert planet where Rey lives at the beginning of 'The Force Awakens'?",
    options: ["Jakku", "Tatooine", "Geonosis", "Pasaana"],
    correctAnswer: "Jakku",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is Anakin Skywalker's Padawan in 'The Clone Wars' series?",
    options: [
      "Ahsoka Tano",
      "Barriss Offee",
      "Luminara Unduli",
      "Aayla Secura",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Ahsoka Tano",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the Sith Lord who trained Darth Sidious?",
    options: ["Darth Plagueis", "Darth Bane", "Darth Revan", "Darth Maul"],
    correctAnswer: "Darth Plagueis",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the planet where Obi-Wan Kenobi and Anakin Skywalker have their final duel?",
    options: ["Mustafar", "Geonosis", "Utapau", "Coruscant"],
    correctAnswer: "Mustafar",
  },
  {
    question: "Who plays Princess Leia in the original trilogy?",
    options: [
      "Carrie Fisher",
      "Natalie Portman",
      "Daisy Ridley",
      "Felicity Jones",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Carrie Fisher",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Anakin Skywalker's mother?",
    options: ["Shmi Skywalker", "Padmé Amidala", "Beru Lars", "Mon Mothma"],
    correctAnswer: "Shmi Skywalker",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the crime lord who puts a bounty on Han Solo?",
    options: ["Jabba the Hutt", "Bib Fortuna", "Maz Kanata", "Dryden Vos"],
    correctAnswer: "Jabba the Hutt",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the forest moon where the second Death Star is destroyed?",
    options: ["Endor", "Yavin 4", "Dagobah", "Scarif"],
    correctAnswer: "Endor",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the Supreme Leader of the First Order in 'The Force Awakens'?",
    options: ["Snoke", "Kylo Ren", "General Hux", "Captain Phasma"],
    correctAnswer: "Snoke",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the planet where Luke Skywalker is in exile in 'The Force Awakens'?",
    options: ["Ahch-To", "Dagobah", "Tatooine", "Crait"],
    correctAnswer: "Ahch-To",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the actor that plays Kylo Ren?",
    options: ["Adam Driver", "Oscar Isaac", "John Boyega", "Domhnall Gleeson"],
    correctAnswer: "Adam Driver",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the droid that delivers the Death Star plans to the Rebel Alliance?",
    options: ["R2-D2", "C-3PO", "BB-8", "K-2SO"],
    correctAnswer: "R2-D2",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the Jedi Knight that discovers the clone army on Kamino?",
    options: ["Obi-Wan Kenobi", "Qui-Gon Jinn", "Mace Windu", "Yoda"],
    correctAnswer: "Obi-Wan Kenobi",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Anakin Skywalker's Padawan braid?",
    options: ["Silka bead", "Jedi braid", "Force strand", "Padawan lock"],
    correctAnswer: "Silka bead",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the leader of the Rebel Alliance in 'A New Hope'?",
    options: [
      "Mon Mothma",
      "Princess Leia",
      "Admiral Ackbar",
      "General Dodonna",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Mon Mothma",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the planet where Anakin Skywalker was born?",
    options: ["Tatooine", "Naboo", "Coruscant", "Kamino"],
    correctAnswer: "Tatooine",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the Sith apprentice that Darth Sidious takes after Darth Maul?",
    options: [
      "Count Dooku",
      "Darth Vader",
      "Asajj Ventress",
      "General Grievous",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Count Dooku",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the cantina where Luke and Obi-Wan meet Han Solo?",
    options: [
      "Mos Eisley Cantina",
      "Maz's Castle",
      "Jabba's Palace",
      "Dex's Diner",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Mos Eisley Cantina",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the actor that plays Finn in the sequel trilogy?",
    options: ["John Boyega", "Oscar Isaac", "Domhnall Gleeson", "Adam Driver"],
    correctAnswer: "John Boyega",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the planet where the Rebel base is located in 'A New Hope'?",
    options: ["Yavin 4", "Hoth", "Dantooine", "Scarif"],
    correctAnswer: "Yavin 4",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the Jedi Master that first discovers Anakin Skywalker on Tatooine?",
    options: ["Qui-Gon Jinn", "Obi-Wan Kenobi", "Mace Windu", "Yoda"],
    correctAnswer: "Qui-Gon Jinn",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the Imperial officer who commands the first Death Star?",
    options: [
      "Grand Moff Tarkin",
      "Admiral Piett",
      "General Veers",
      "Director Krennic",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Grand Moff Tarkin",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the actor that plays Poe Dameron in the sequel trilogy?",
    options: ["Oscar Isaac", "John Boyega", "Adam Driver", "Domhnall Gleeson"],
    correctAnswer: "Oscar Isaac",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the planet where Jyn Erso is hiding at the beginning of 'Rogue One'?",
    options: ["Lah'mu", "Jedha", "Eadu", "Scarif"],
    correctAnswer: "Lah'mu",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the Mandalorian warrior who leads Death Watch in 'The Clone Wars' series?",
    options: ["Pre Vizsla", "Bo-Katan Kryze", "Sabine Wren", "Gar Saxon"],
    correctAnswer: "Pre Vizsla",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the Wookiee co-pilot of the Millennium Falcon?",
    options: ["Chewbacca", "Tarfful", "Zaalbar", "Lowbacca"],
    correctAnswer: "Chewbacca",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the actor that plays young Han Solo in 'Solo: A Star Wars Story'?",
    options: [
      "Alden Ehrenreich",
      "Harrison Ford",
      "Anthony Ingruber",
      "Ansel Elgort",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Alden Ehrenreich",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the planet where Luke Skywalker trains Rey in 'The Last Jedi'?",
    options: ["Ahch-To", "Dagobah", "Skellig Michael", "Crait"],
    correctAnswer: "Ahch-To",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the Sith Lord that Darth Sidious mentions in 'Revenge of the Sith'?",
    options: ["Darth Plagueis", "Darth Bane", "Darth Revan", "Darth Tyranus"],
    correctAnswer: "Darth Plagueis",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of the Imperial superweapon in 'Rogue One'?",
    options: ["Death Star", "Starkiller Base", "Sun Crusher", "Galaxy Gun"],
    correctAnswer: "Death Star",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the actor that plays Cassian Andor in 'Rogue One' and the 'Andor' series?",
    options: ["Diego Luna", "Riz Ahmed", "Mads Mikkelsen", "Alan Tudyk"],
    correctAnswer: "Diego Luna",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the planet where Anakin Skywalker and Padmé Amidala get married?",
    options: ["Naboo", "Coruscant", "Alderaan", "Geonosis"],
    correctAnswer: "Naboo",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the Jedi Master that sacrifices himself to allow the Rebels to escape in 'The Last Jedi'?",
    options: ["Luke Skywalker", "Yoda", "Obi-Wan Kenobi", "Mace Windu"],
    correctAnswer: "Luke Skywalker",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the name of the Imperial officer who leads the attack on Hoth in 'The Empire Strikes Back'?",
    options: [
      "General Veers",
      "Admiral Piett",
      "Captain Needa",
      "Grand Moff Tarkin",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "General Veers",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Who is the actor that plays Lando Calrissian in the original trilogy?",
    options: [
      "Billy Dee Williams",
      "Donald Glover",
      "Samuel L. Jackson",
      "Laurence Fishburne",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Billy Dee Williams",
  },
];

export default StarWarsQuestions;
